<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Life Trivia on ButterCat</title>
    <link>https://htsod.github.io/life_trivia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life Trivia on ButterCat</description>
    <image>
      <title>ButterCat</title>
      <url>https://htsod.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.123.7</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://htsod.github.io/life_trivia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Review of Continuous Phase Transition, Ginzburg-Landau Equation and Renormalization Group</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/life_trivia/gl_eqn_criticality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/life_trivia/gl_eqn_criticality/</guid>
      <description>Title A concise and descriptive title that captures the essence of your research project.
Abstract A brief summary of the research project, highlighting the key research question, methodology, expected outcomes, and significance.
Introduction Background: Provide a comprehensive overview of the relevant physics concepts and current understanding of the research area.
Motivation: Explain the rationale behind your research, including the gap in knowledge or unanswered questions you aim to address.
Literature Review Relevant Studies: Critically analyze existing research related to your topic, highlighting key findings, limitations, and potential areas for further exploration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Full-Marathon</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/life_trivia/first_marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/life_trivia/first_marathon/</guid>
      <description>When I&amp;#39;m running, I will enter a great mental state. No matter how I felt before the run, I always end up feeling relieved and refreshed afterward.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Variational Method as Approximation to Simplify Quantum Circuit</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/life_trivia/nisq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/life_trivia/nisq/</guid>
      <description>Preview This blog provides a concise overview of some key noise-resilient, intermediate-scale quantum algorithms, designed for a general audience. We&amp;rsquo;ll first explore the core mechanics of these algorithms, followed by their applicability to existing classical counterparts. Lastly, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the hardware requirements necessary to implement these algorithms, with a focus on managing noise in quantum systems.
Variational Quantum Eigenvalue (VQE) With the quantum hardware progressing, promising quantum algorithm has been devised to harness the exotic nature of quantum computer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study Notes on Network Theory</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/life_trivia/network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/life_trivia/network/</guid>
      <description>This blog aims to summerize the essential theory and method of network study.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
