<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>ButterCat</title>
    <link>https://htsod.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ButterCat</description>
    <image>
      <title>ButterCat</title>
      <url>https://htsod.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.123.7</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://htsod.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Before you read: Here are the updates</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/posts/read_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/posts/read_me/</guid>
      <description>Updates 2024/10/11 Distinguishing Microscopic and Emergent Properties Microscopic theories, whether classical or quantum mechanics, do not inherently lead to an increase in entropy. Entropy is an emergent property, arising from the complex interactions of many-body systems. In some cases, we can simplify the behavior of weakly perturbed systems by adding microscopic interactions. However, in strongly interacting systems, complexity increases, often requiring nonlinear models. Yet, we can still derive meaningful rules at the phenomenological level to describe emergent patterns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ginzburg-Landau Eqaution and its Applications</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/posts/gl_eqn_application/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/posts/gl_eqn_application/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phases Transition in Random Graphs</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/posts/small_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/posts/small_world/</guid>
      <description>This investigation effort started off from a problem sets in a amazing statistical mechanics textbook by James Sethna. ( Citation: 2021,&amp;#32;pp.&amp;nbsp;10-13 Sethna,&amp;#32; J.&amp;#32; (2021). &amp;#32; Statistical mechanics: Entropy, order parameters, and complexity. &amp;#32; OUP Oxford.&amp;#32;Retrieved from&amp;#32; https://books.google.com/books?id=anEWEAAAQBAJ ) Six degree of separation: a inquiry about social cloesness In addition to your cloesest aquitances, if you know six people preferrably internationally, then you basically could connect to everyone in this globe in a effective way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Study on Tight-binding and Free electron Model</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/posts/free_tight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/posts/free_tight/</guid>
      <description>Sommerfeld free electron model Sommerfeld free electron model describe \( N \) number of fermions without any interaction, not even the columbic interaction between those \(N\) electron. Therefore, the model is more like the study of fermions statistics without charge.
Theory The statistical properties of fermions with a occupation function of
$$n_{F}(\beta (E-\mu))= \frac{1}{e^{\beta (E-\mu)}+1}$$
Also meaning the number of electrons allowed at energy \( E \) and chemical potential \( \mu \).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fourier Transforms: A Group Theoretic Perspective</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/posts/fourier/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/posts/fourier/</guid>
      <description>Group theory is powerful in analysis problem with symmetry. This blog aims at giving an example on how Fourier Theorem could be derived on the ground of group theory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Mechanical Historian</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/posts/wave_particle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/posts/wave_particle/</guid>
      <description>Both the Schrödinger wave equation and the Heisenberg matrix method are fundamental approaches to quantum mechanics, each offering a unique perspective. To unify them, we recognize that while they approach the problem differently, they ultimately describe the same quantum phenomena.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Full-Marathon</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/life_trivia/first_marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/life_trivia/first_marathon/</guid>
      <description>When I&amp;#39;m running, I will enter a great mental state. No matter how I felt before the run, I always end up feeling relieved and refreshed afterward.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solving the Ising Model</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/posts/ising_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/posts/ising_model/</guid>
      <description>This blogh reprodcues the transfer matrix solution to one dimensional Ising model and the numerical solution to the two dimensional Ising model. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study Notes on Group Theory</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/review/group_theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/review/group_theory/</guid>
      <description>From permutation to group theory Everyone knows permutation. Permutation counts the number of ways that we can exchange a set of element. Take a simple example of permutation of three objects naming it with integer (123). There are \( 3!=6 \) ways of rearranging these three elements into different orders. Let&amp;rsquo;s list out all the six orders:
$$ (123), (132), (231), (213), (312), (321)$$
Looking at a different perspective, we can also treat each permutation of the element \( (123) \) as a transformation to \( (123) \).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study Notes on Statistical Mechanics</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/review/statistical_mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/review/statistical_mechanics/</guid>
      <description>Entropy, Order Parameters and Complexity What is statistical mechanics? Ensemble How to connect microscopic law with macroscopic phenomenon? The concept of ensemble provides a method that connects the two. Treating a large system(macroscopic) as collection of similarly prepared systems(microscopic).
Entropy Entropy to be defined as a function of probability distribution \(p_{i}\) must satisfy the following:
Maximum at \(\frac{1}{p_{i}}\) Minimum at \(p_{i} = 0 , S = 0\) Minimum at \(p_{i} = 1, S = 0\) The unique function that satisfies the above requirement is \(S=-p_{i}\log{p_{i}}\), giving rise to the information interpretation of entropy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Variational Method as Approximation to Simplify Quantum Circuit</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/posts/nisq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/posts/nisq/</guid>
      <description>Preview This blog provides a concise overview of some key noise-resilient, intermediate-scale quantum algorithms, designed for a general audience. We&amp;rsquo;ll first explore the core mechanics of these algorithms, followed by their applicability to existing classical counterparts. Lastly, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the hardware requirements necessary to implement these algorithms, with a focus on managing noise in quantum systems.
Variational Quantum Eigenvalue (VQE) With the quantum hardware progressing, promising quantum algorithm has been devised to harness the exotic nature of quantum computer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study Notes on Network Theory</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/review/network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/review/network/</guid>
      <description>This blog aims to summerize the essential theory and method of network study.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study Notes on Quantum Mechanics</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/review/quantum_mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/review/quantum_mechanics/</guid>
      <description>Preview If one struggle to convince themselves the sanity of quantum mechanics, the best advice to them is to move on and put yourself into practical question and work out the math. That&amp;rsquo;s the core spirit of this reivew note about. All we need to know is the necessary axioms which were verified long ago, and then to make use of these axioms to draw meaningful observation on the theory itself or practical problems to draw in more intuition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top-down derivation of Electromagnetism</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/posts/maxwell_eqns_derive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/posts/maxwell_eqns_derive/</guid>
      <description>Relativity&amp;rsquo;s action principle constrains how light and matter interact within spacetime. By placing the potential term either inside or outside the action square root, we derive the familiar interactions of gravity or electromagnetism between matter. This post offers a top-down view of electromagnetism&amp;rsquo;s derivation from these fundamental principles.
Relativistic Action To incorporate relativistic effects, the action is written as:
$$ S = -m \int{ \sqrt{-\eta_{\mu \nu} dx^{\mu} dx^{\nu}} } = -m \sqrt{dt^{2} - d\vec{x}^{2}} $$</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renormalization Group method with Examples</title>
      <link>https://htsod.github.io/posts/rg_method/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://htsod.github.io/posts/rg_method/</guid>
      <description>Renormalization Group Approach in Dynamical System The renormalization group (RG) method is an approximation technique initially developed for solving strongly interacting many-body problems in quantum field theory, where perturbative solutions deviate from the actual solutions. The fundamental concept of the renormalization group approach is to eliminate irrelevant degrees of freedom in a physical system while preserving its essential characteristics ( Citation: P. Kopietz,&amp;#32;2010 P. Kopietz,&amp;#32; F.&amp;#32; (2010). &amp;#32; Introduction to the Functional Renormalization Group (1).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
